Frederik DeVilder

|UX/UI Designer

www.velddie<u>r.com</u>

© 07930 350331

welddier@gmail.com

Greater Manchester

Certified trained UX designer and overall digital design specialist with a strong background in interdisciplinary design for software, web, and digital media, using their talent for problem solving in everyday UX and their everbroadening fascination and knowledge of modern web-focussed design and front-end development.

■ EXPERIENCE

Lead Visual Designer

Visual design | Directing | Web design | Motion design | Customer experience | Design consulting

Freelance Media Designer

Consultation | Visual design | Ecommerce | Brand design | Content for web | Web hosting | Photography | Photoshop | After Effects | Illustrator

Office Assistant

Punctuality | MS Office | all-round assistance | Flexible responsibilities

Nederlandse Notariskluis, Netherlands, E-Business, (Mar 2018-Sept 2018)

- Leading efforts in improving customer experience and conversion rates for fast-growing start-up by revamping visual style and accessibility of website.
- Designed brand style and directed production of visual material that improved the customer's understanding of the product, increasing interaction and conversion rates.

Various clients, Netherlands, Freelance, (Apr 2016-Nov 2019)

- Designed and created various materials, brand design, promotional material, website design, meeting client standards and expectations of quality, helping improve B2C and user experience quality.
- Assisted small businesses with transition towards using e-commerce CMS paired with tailored style and design, increasing their potential customer base.

Notarispraktijk Interwaert, Netherlands, (Jun 2010-May 2012)

- Fulfilled varying office and administrative duties and learned using office software in a professional setting.
- Responsibilities emphasised on flexibility, punctuality, and the timely and successful completion of objective-based tasks.

■ PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Professional Certified UX Designer

UX design | UX research | Analysis | User testing | Product research | Adobe Xd | Sketch | Prototyping | Running user sessions | Agile | UI Design

Advanced CSS and Sass

HTML/CSS | JavaScript | SCSS | Sass | Flexbox | CSS Grid | Responsive Design | NPM Scripts | Animation UX Design Institute, Glasgow Caledonian University, Diploma, (Oct 2019—Jun 2020)

- Certification as professional UX designer, with proven proficiency in the research and design of powerful user-centred apps by building a desktop airline booking experience, and in graded examination with top results.
- Ensuring success rates by running user testing sessions, testing designs with interactive prototypes, following design principles, and following a flexible and iterating Agile development cycle.

Udemy, Online, (Mar 2020-Jul 2020)

- Advanced my proficiency in web design by mastering CSS, SCSS and Sass, learning from real-life application and by studying material with emphasis on modern and responsive design for most common devices.
- Used modern web development tools and conventions such as preprocessed CSS, development packages, CSS grid / flex, and scalable design systems, ensuring well-organized and adjustable websites.

■ EDUCATION

Visual design: Multimedia

Motion design | Graphic design | Design for web | Adobe CC | Animation | Media design | After Effects | Illustrator | Photoshop | Premiere Pro | Lightroom | Logic Pro X

Design for Web

Web coding | Fundamental HTML/CSS | Web hosting | Front-end web development Chaffey College, CA, USA, Associate in Arts (AA), (2012-2016)

 Multimedia design degree revolving around the mastering of interdisciplinary digital design skills using industry tools and software, such as After Effects, Photoshop, Premier, with demonstrated proficiency in multiple projects and the creation of content for various visual media, graduating top of class and qualifying for the selected student honours programme.

Chaffey College, CA, USA, Associate in Arts (AA), (2012-2016)

 Explored key concepts of HTML5/CSS/JS web development with emphasis on design, using the fundamental conventions of building multilayer websites, while further addressing theoretical topics of web and web development in a classroom environment.

■ SKILLS & QUALITIES

UX Skills

Prototyping

Skills in building different level fidelity prototypes for showcase and testing, with best applied example found in my FlyUX project.

Research

Use various methods of research in my projects, such as competitor audits, user testing, affinity diagrams and persona building.

User Interface design

Build beautiful responsive interfaces based on usability, inclusivity, and pixel-precise design.

IA & Diagram design

High diligence designing diagrams to convey IA design, flow maps, and navigation design, assisting in the delivery of final products.

Usability testing

Experienced user testing, usability tests, interviews, surveys, with best applied example in my FlyUX case study.

Wireframe delivery

Creating highly descriptive documentation in visual and writing format to aid the development process in the best possible way.

l use...

Xd / Framer / Invision to design and create interactive prototypes for testing.

HTML/CSS/JS to build high-quality responsive webpages for desktop and mobile.

Photoshop / Illustrator to design and alter graphics with precision.

Pen & Paper / Balsamiq to create drafts and brainstorm ideas.

UML to build informative diagrams, interaction pipelines and flows for design and software experiences.

+ Adobe CC / ES16 / OBS / Miro / Visual studio code / etc...

Applying qualities like...

- User empathy,
- Attention to detail,
- Analytical thinking,
- Motivated self-learning,
- Effective problem solving,

- Creative confidence.
- Clear communication,
- Effective Collaboration,
- Constructive critiquing.